{"name": "61B  2008", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. If r = 7, b = 4, and g = -8, what does (r + b - g)(b + g) equal?", "choices": {"A": " -76", "B": "-12", "C": "12", "D": "15", "E": "76"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Tasha's regular pay is $12.00 per hour for a 40-hour workweek. For each hour over 40 hours she works in a week, she is paid  times her regular hourly pay. How much is Tasha paid for a week in which she works 49 hours?", "choices": {"A": "$588.00", "B": "$601.50", "C": "$642.00", "D": "$661.50", "E": "$882.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. To attend the Press Club Annual Banquet, members pay $40 per ticket, while nonmembers pay $50 per ticket. What is the revenue, in dollars, from the tickets when 100 member tickets and n nonmember tickets are purchased?", "choices": {"A": "n + 100 ", "B": "50n + 40(100) ", "C": "50(n + 100) ", "D": "50(n + 40) ", "E": "(50 + 40)n"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. How many integers between 9 and 59 can be divided by 5 with a remainder of zero?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "10", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "13"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Of the 200 parking spaces in a parking lot, 4% of the spaces are reserved for handicapped parking, and 12 of he nonhandicapped spaces are suitable for compact cars only. How many spaces that are NOT reserved for handicapped parking are suitable for noncompact cars?", "choices": {"A": "192", "B": "188", "C": "184", "D": "180", "E": "168"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The shadows of a fence post and a nearby flagpole (both vertical and on level ground) were measured at the same time. The fence post's shadow was 3 ft long, and the flagpole's shadow was 10 ft long. If the fence post is 6 ft tall, about how many feet tall is the flagpole?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "18", "C": "20", "D": "22", "E": "30"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. -5(|-3 + 8|) = ?", "choices": {"A": "-55", "B": "-25", "C": "0", "D": "25", "E": "55"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. A 5-inch-by-6-inch rectangle is cut along its diagonal to form 2 triangles. What is the area of each triangle, in square inches ?", "choices": {"A": "5.5", "B": "7.5", "C": "11", "D": "15", "E": "30"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Franco is riding in a seat on a Ferris wheel. The whee rotates at a constant rate of 1 revolution every minute. What is the measure of the angle franco's seat rotates around the center of the Ferris wheel, starting at the bottom, in minute?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "180\u00b0", "E": "360\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Which of the following calculations gives the area in square centimeters, of the square below, with sides 8 centimeters long?", "choices": {"A": "8 + 8", "B": "8 + 8 + 8 + 8", "C": "8 \u00b7 8", "D": "8 \u00b7 8 \u00b7 8 \u00b7 8", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. A recipe for 1 loaf of bread calls for  cups of flour. What is the maximum number of such loaves that can be made with a bag of flour that contains  cups of flour?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "9", "D": "15", "E": "16"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The expression (3c - 2d)(2c + d) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "6c\u00b2 - 7cd - 2d\u00b2", "B": "6c\u00b2 - 7cd + 2d\u00b2", "C": "6c\u00b2- cd - 2d\u00b2", "D": "6c\u00b2 - cd + 2d\u00b2", "E": "6c\u00b2 - 2d\u00b2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Eight points with integer coordinates are plotted in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Which of the plotted points has an x-coordinate less than 1 and a y-coordinate of at least 2 \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "A", "B": "B", "C": "C", "D": "D", "E": "E"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. When George fell asleep one night, the temperature was 28\u00b0 Fahrenheit. When George awoke the next morning, the temperature was -15\u00b0 Fahrenheit. Which of the following, where + denotes a rise in temperature and - denotes a drop in temperature, best illustrates the temperature change from the time George fell asleep until the time he awoke?", "choices": {"A": "-43\u00b0F", "B": "-13\u00b0F", "C": "-7\u00b0F", "D": "+13\u00b0F", "E": "+43\u00b0F"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Ohm's law for electricity is I = , where I is the current flow in amperes, E is the number of volts, and R is the number of ohms of resistance. A technician has a circuit with a resistance of 34 ohms and a current flow of 7 amperes. Which of the following expressions gives the number of volts for this circuit?", "choices": {"A": "34 + 7", "B": "34 - 7", "C": "34 \u00b7 7", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. In the figure below, AC || DF,  \u25b3EBF is isosceles with EB \u224c FB, and \u2220CBF measures 35\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220DEB?", "choices": {"A": "\u00b0", "B": "110\u00b0", "C": "125\u00b0", "D": "135\u00b0", "E": "145\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. A sequence of 5 numbers has 6 as its first term and 32 as its last term. The first 3 numbers are an arithmetic sequence. The last 3 numbers are a geometric sequence with a common ratio of 2. What is the common difference among the first 3 terms?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "61", "D": "67", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Water in Lake Forman is frozen at Celsius temperatures at or below 0\u00b0. Which of the following expressions represents all the Celsius temperatures, T, at which water is frozen in Lake Forman?", "choices": {"A": "T = 0 ", "B": "T &gt; 0 ", "C": "T \u2265 0", "D": "T \uff1c 0", "E": "T \u2264 0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Sarah swims in a rectangular-shaped swimming pool 18 feet wide and 24 feet long. About how many feet long is a diagonal of the surface of the water in the pool?", "choices": {"A": "21", "B": "30", "C": "42", "D": "441", "E": "900"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Let a, b, c, and d be a positive real numbers such that  . Which of the numbers a, b, c, or d is the greatest?", "choices": {"A": "a", "B": "b", "C": "c", "D": "d", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. What value of x makes the equation 7x - 3(2x - 4) = 10 true?", "choices": {"A": "-12", "B": "-2", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "22"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following (x,y) pairs is the solution for the system of equations x + 2y = 5 and -2x + y = 10?", "choices": {"A": "(-3,4)", "B": "(-1,3)", "C": "(1,2) ", "D": "(5,0)", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. For nonzero numbers x and y, which of the following expressions is NOT equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. In the figure below, the interior of a square with 5-inch sides is partitioned into smaller squares with 1-inch sides. The interior of the small square at the center of the figure and the interiors of all of the small squares that share at least 1 side with the large square are shaded. What percent of the interior of the large square is shaded?", "choices": {"A": "17% ", "B": "50% ", "C": "% ", "D": "68% ", "E": "84%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. A researcher observed the growth of a certain colony of bacteria and recorded the data shown below.For the days observed, which of the following expressions best approximates the number of cells in the colony on the nth day?", "choices": {"A": "100n", "B": "300n", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Smiley the Clown charges $10 for scheduling a party and $5 per hour after arriving at the party. Happy the Clown charges $10 per hour for a party but does not have a charge for scheduling a party. The graph below shows the 2 clowns wages, with h as the number of hours worked for a party.For what range of hours worked for a party does Happy the Clown make as much or more than Smiley the Clown?", "choices": {"A": "h \u2265 0 ", "B": "h \u2264 2 ", "C": "0 \u2264 h \u2264 2 ", "D": "h \u2265 2", "E": "There is no range for which Happy the Clown will make as much or more than Smiley the Clown."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Which of the following is an equation of the line that passes through the points (1,-2) and (4,7) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "y = x - 2 ", "B": "y = 3x - 5", "C": "y = 4x + 7", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In the figure below, A, C, and E are collinear; \u25b3ABC and \u25b3ADC are as shown; and angle measures are as marked. What is the value of p?", "choices": {"A": "110", "B": "58", "C": "55", "D": "46", "E": "23"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. The diameter of a circle is 10 centimeters. What is its circumference, in centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "5\u03c0", "B": "10\u03c0", "C": "20\u03c0", "D": "25\u03c0", "E": "100\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. A day care center has 160 feet of fence that was donated to construct a fence around a play area. The area is to be rectangular with its length 12 feet longer than its width. Assuming all of the fence is used, what will be the approximate dimensions, in feet, of the play area?", "choices": {"A": "28 by 40 ", "B": "34 by 46 ", "C": "36 by 44 ", "D": "40 by 40 ", "E": "74 by 86"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. An angle in a right triangle has measure \u03b1. If sin \u03b1 =  and tan \u03b1 = \uff0cthen cos \u03b1 = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. What is the distance, in coordinate units, between (6,4) and (8,10) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "4", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. One of the following is the slope of the line graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A formula for the area of a trapezoid is A = (b1 + b2)h, where A is the area, b1 and b2 are the lengths of the bases, and h is the height of the trapezoid. In terms of A, b1 and b2,  h = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following equations has the pressure P varying directly as the square of the temperature T and inversely as the volume V?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Which of the following is NOT a factor of z5 - 16z ?", "choices": {"A": "z2 - 1", "B": "z2 - 4", "C": "z + 2", "D": "z", "E": "z - 2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. What is the sine of \u03b1 in the right triangle shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In the figure below, AE and BD intersect at C, and the measure of \u2220E is twice the measure of \u2220D. The measure of \u2220A is 40\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220B is 32\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220E ?", "choices": {"A": "24\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "48\u00b0", "D": "72\u00b0", "E": "108\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In the figure below, the measure of \u2220BAC is greater than the measure of \u2220DAC and AB = AD. Which of the following statements must be true?", "choices": {"A": "AB &gt; BC", "B": "BC &lt; DC ", "C": "BC = DC ", "D": "BC &gt; DC ", "E": "AB + BC = AC"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. In a math course, a student scored 100 on one test, 97 on another test, and 88 on each of the other tests. The students test average for the course, where each test weighted equally, is exactly 91. What is the total umber of math tests that the student has taken in the course ? ", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "5", "C": "7", "D": "15", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. An equation of a particular circle is (x - 3)2 + y2 = 10. What are the coordinates of this circle's center and what is the length, in coordinate units, of this circle's radius?", "choices": {"A": "Center: (-3,0);      Radius:  ", "B": "Center: (-3,0);      Radius: 5", "C": "Center: (3,0);       Radius: ", "D": "Center: (3,0);       Radius: 5", "E": "Center: (3,0);       Radius: 10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The point(3,-4) is the midpoint of the line segment the standard (x, y) coordinate plane joining the point (8,-11) and the point (a, b). Which of the following is (a,b) ?", "choices": {"A": "(-2,3)", "B": "(-2,-19)", "C": "(2,-3)", "D": "(2.5,-3.5)", "E": "(5.5,-7.5)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. If AC = 10 feet and BD = 12 feet in the rhombus ABCD shown below, what is its area, in square feet ?", "choices": {"A": "11", "B": "22", "C": "30", "D": "60", "E": "120"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A right, triangular prism that is 10 feet long, 4 feet wide, and 3 feet tall is shown below. What is its volume, in cubic feet ?", "choices": {"A": "50", "B": "60", "C": "84", "D": "114", "E": "120"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Use the following information to answer questions 46-49.A balloonist collecting data on pollutants at various levels above the ground takes off at 8:00 A.M. When the balloon is in motion, it moves only straight up or straight down and at a constant speed within each hour-long interval. The balloon is at an altitude that is a multiple of 100 meters at the beginning of each hour. The balloon lands at 2:00 P.M. at the same spot from which it took off. The altitude of the balloon, in meters above the ground, is shown in the figure below.46. Which of the following is closest to the total distance, in meters, that the balloonist traveled from 10:00 A.M. to 1:00 PM.?", "choices": {"A": "400 ", "B": "500 ", "C": "600 ", "D": "680 ", "E": "700"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Use the following information to answer questions 46-49.A balloonist collecting data on pollutants at various levels above the ground takes off at 8:00 A.M. When the balloon is in motion, it moves only straight up or straight down and at a constant speed within each hour-long interval. The balloon is at an altitude that is a multiple of 100 meters at the beginning of each hour. The balloon lands at 2:00 P.M. at the same spot from which it took off. The altitude of the balloon, in meters above the ground, is shown in the figure below.47.  What was the total time, in hours and minutes, that the balloon was at least 200 meters above the ground?", "choices": {"A": "1 hour 30 minutes ", "B": "1 hour 36 minutes ", "C": "3 hours 0 minutes ", "D": "3 hours 6 minutes ", "E": "3 hours 48 minutes"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Use the following information to answer questions 46-49.A balloonist collecting data on pollutants at various levels above the ground takes off at 8:00 A.M. When the balloon is in motion, it moves only straight up or straight down and at a constant speed within each hour-long interval. The balloon is at an altitude that is a multiple of 100 meters at the beginning of each hour. The balloon lands at 2:00 P.M. at the same spot from which it took off. The altitude of the balloon, in meters above the ground, is shown in the figure below.48. Which of the following graphs best represents the absolute value of the balloon's velocity, in meters per hour, between 8:00 A.M. and 2:00 P.M. ? (Note: Ignore acceleration and deceleration.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Use the following information to answer questions 46-49.A balloonist collecting data on pollutants at various levels above the ground takes off at 8:00 A.M. When the balloon is in motion, it moves only straight up or straight down and at a constant speed within each hour-long interval. The balloon is at an altitude that is a multiple of 100 meters at the beginning of each hour. The balloon lands at 2:00 P.M. at the same spot from which it took off. The altitude of the balloon, in meters above the ground, is shown in the figure below.49. Which of the following phrases best describes the balloon's motion between 10:30 A.M. and 12:00 noon?", "choices": {"A": "Descended, and then ascended more quickly ", "B": "Descended, and then ascended more slowly ", "C": "Stayed at the same altitude ", "D": "Ascended, and then descended more quickly ", "E": "Ascended, and then descended more slowly"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane shown below, \u25b3ABC has vertices at A(-2,3), B(-2,1), and C(-1,1). A translation is performed on \u25b3ABC, and the image of each point P with coordinates (x,y) is the point P' with coordinates (x',y') where x' = x + 3 and y' = y - 2. The vertices of \u25b3A'B'C' are in which quadrant(s)?", "choices": {"A": "Quadrant I only ", "B": "Quadrant II only ", "C": "Quadrant III only ", "D": "Quadrants I and IV only ", "E": "Quadrants II and III only"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the figure below, AB \u224c CD. Fred wants to apply the Side-Angle-Side (SAS) congruence theorem to prove that \u25b3ABD \u224c \u25b3CDB. Which of the following congruences, if established, is sufficient?", "choices": {"A": "\u2220A \u224c \u2220C ", "B": "\u22203 \u224c \u22204 ", "C": "\u22202 \u224c \u22204 ", "D": "\u22202 \u224c \u22203 ", "E": "\u22201 \u224c \u22204"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. A camper at Site C sends a distress signal. The signal is received by both Ranger Station A and Ranger Station B. As shown below, Ranger Station A is 6 miles directly west of Ranger Station B. Ranger Station A is directly south of Site C. The entire region is flat and level. On a map, the angle formed at Ranger Station B by drawing straight lines from Ranger Station B to Site C and to Ranger Station A measures 57\u00b0. About how many miles away from Site C is the closer of the 2 ranger stations ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "6 sin 57\u00b0", "D": "6 cos 57\u00b0", "E": "6 tan 57\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. If the diameter of a circle is tripled, the area of the resulting circle is how many times the area of the original circle?", "choices": {"A": "1.5", "B": "2.25", "C": "3", "D": "6", "E": "9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Only tenth-, eleventh-, and twelfth-grade students attend Washington High School. The ratio of tenth graders to the school's total student population is 86:255, and the ratio of eleventh graders to the school's total student population is 18:51. If 1 student is chosen at random from the entire school, which grade is that student most likely to be in?", "choices": {"A": "Tenth ", "B": "Eleventh ", "C": "Twelfth ", "D": "All grades are equally likely.", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. When x and y are nonzero real numbers such that |x| = -x and |y| = y, which of the following must be positive?", "choices": {"A": "xy", "B": "xy", "C": "x - y ", "D": "x + y", "E": "y - x"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. If , then  = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Kelly asked 120 students questions about skiing. The results of the poll are shown in the table below.After completing the poll, Kelly wondered how many of the students polled had skied both cross-country and downhill. How many of the students polled indicated that they had skied both cross-country and downhill ?", "choices": {"A": "73", "B": "65", "C": "47", "D": "18", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. A right triangle has legs of length 25 sin \u03b8 feet and 25 cos \u03b8 feet for some angle \u03b8 that satisfies 0\u00b0 &lt; \u03b8 &lt; 90\u00b0. What is the length, in feet, of the longest side of the triangle?", "choices": {"A": "\u03b8", "B": "1", "C": "5", "D": "25", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. For all nonzero x, y, and z such that x = yz, which of the following must be equivalent to xy?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "yz2", "C": "yz", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. When -3 \u2264 x \u2264 4 and -1 \u2264 y \u2264 2, what is the least possible value for x - y ?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "-2", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "A"}]}